最初  宇宙是一片黑暗
In the beginning, there was darkness
紧接着一声巨响  混沌初开
and then, bang, giving birth to
时间  空间和物质开始不断膨胀
an endless expanding existence of time, space and matter.
每天  我们都在解密这神秘莫测
Every day, new discoveries are unlocking
彗星撞击木星
新发现的行星
令人疯狂的极端之地
the mysterious, the mind-blowing,
冲向地球的流星
宇宙
the deadly secrets of a place we call the universe.
由太阳喷发
It bursts from the Sun
相当于核武器一万倍的能量
with the power of 10,000 nuclear weapons
径直冲向地球
heading straight for Earth.
想到整块大陆的所有电网都彻底摧毁
Think of totally destroying the power grid of an entire continent.
电视  收音机  因特网都将停止运转
Television, radio, Internet all down.
全世界的自来水  燃料供给
So is running water, fuel deliveries,
食品和杂货店都无一幸免
food and groceries across the globe.
这些磁暴的影响是全球性的
These storms have a planetary footprint.
很多人会因此而丧生
And the potential for loss of life is quite large.
不到一年  就有数百万人死亡
Within a year, millions of people are dead.
国家基础设施被彻底毁灭
National infrastructures are ruined and may never come back.
这不是灾难片
This isn't a disaster film.
这是美国国家科学院在2009年的一份研究报告
This is a 2009 research report from the National Academy of Sciences.
有人预言  报告所描述的全球灾难即将来临
And some say the global catastrophe it outlines may be coming soon.
这一次迟迟未到
We're overdue.
太阳磁力
Solar magnetism.
为何如此致命  令人费解呢
Why is it so deadly and so miSunderstood?
我们能做些什么
And is there anything we can do
以避免磁暴所带来的影响呢
to escape the magnetic storm?
--==本影片由 CMCT 团队 荣誉出品==--
更多精彩影视 请访问 http://cmct.cc
影片压制&调校:无影  字幕来源:人人影视  招募Q号:76846146
宇
宙
磁 暴
第5季　第3集
2013年  春天
Spring, 2013.
北极光在纽约  芝加哥
The northern lights dazzle millions in the night skies above New York, Chicago,
华盛顿和整个欧洲上空发出耀眼光芒
Washington D.C., and across Europe.
这些极光的产生源于日冕物质抛射
These auroras are the result of a Coronal Mass Ejection.
或称为CME
Also known as a CME,
这是来自太阳的巨大的磁耀斑
It's a massive magnetic flare from the Sun.
这种极强的磁场就像是太阳表面发生的爆炸
The extreme magnetic field is like an explosion on the surface of the Sun,
特拉维斯·斯·泰勒
物理学家
磁场等同于10的25次幂焦耳的能量
and it's 10 to the 25 joules worth of energy.
比人类制造的最大的核装置所产生的能量
That's a hundred million times more energy
还要强一亿倍
than the largest nuclear device that man has ever made.
数十亿吨的太阳物质向宇宙中喷射
Billions of tons of solar material fired off into space...
带电的  磁极化的物质
Electrically charged, magnetically polarized,
直向我们侵袭而来
aimed directly at us.
托德·霍克斯马
斯坦福大学
这些物质宽度足有十万英里
These things are the size of, well, they're a hundred-thousand miles across.
是太阳体积的三分之一
They're a third the size of the Sun.
它就像是整条快速流动的密西西比河
So it's like accelerating the whole Mississippi river
以每小时一百万英里的速度流向地球
and making it move at a million miles an hour toward the Earth.
NASA戈达德航天飞行中心的科学家们
Scientists at NASA's Goddard space center
NASA:美国国家航空航天局
观察了此次太阳耀斑
observe the solar flare,
日冕物质抛射移动速度之快超出人们预料
but the CME is moving faster than anticipated.
人们首次看到北极光之后  不到90秒
90 seconds after citizens first see the northern lights,
这块大陆的大部分就已陷入一片黑暗
most of the continent goes dark.
磁暴通过电线发射出极高的电压
The magnetic storm sends ultra-high voltage
横扫北美洲
through power lines across north America.
它创造了一个真正的强力磁场
It creates a really strong magnetic field
不断吸进新的电流
that induces another current and so on,
电流变得越来越强  直至融化电线
and the current gets so strong it melts the wire
最后释放出很大的能量
and then you got a lot of energy being released.
导致变压器爆炸
It explodes the transformer.
不同城市中巨大的变压器相继爆炸
Giant transformers explode in city after city.
所有的电力消失殆尽
All electricity disappears.
卫星被烧毁  通讯因而中断
So do communications as satellites are burnt out.
没有电话  没有电视
There are no phones, no television,
没有收音机  没有因特网
no radio, no Internet.
所有的基础设施被毁
The whole infrastructure would be damaged.
我们将失去通讯
We wouldn't have communications.
我们将失去很多东西
We wouldn't have so many different things.
停电时间是漫长的
And the electricity will not be coming back.
一场磁暴就足以毁灭大部分的变压器
We could damage enough transformers in one storm
全世界共同努力  需要几年的时间
that it would take several years of the entire world's manufacturing capability
约翰·凯朋玛
电网专家  太阳风暴分析顾问
才能重建被毁的变压器
to replace all of those damaged transformers.
没有电  基础设施就会瘫痪
Without power, infrastructure collapses.
首先影响到的是  水
The first thing to go: Water.
水泵没有电
Without electricity for pumps,
一天之内  城市里的水管就会干涸
city tap water will go dry within a day.
油泵和加油站也是一样
The same is true for gas pumps and gas stations.
无油供应
没有燃料  国家货运停滞
Without fuel, national trucking stops.
食物也没法送到杂货店
So do food deliveries to grocery stores.
人们无法离开城市  因为他们的车没有燃料
People can't leave the cities because their gas tanks are empty.
他们用不了信用卡或者自动取款机
They can't use their credit cards or ATMs
因为没有电源和电话连接
without electrical power and phone connections.
没有电  没有油  没有食物
No power, no gas, no food,
没有水  看不到希望
no water, and no end in sight.
想到整块大陆的所有电网都彻底摧毁
Think of totally destroying the power grid of an entire continent.
我们好似基本上回到了黑暗时代
We would be basically put back in the dark ages.
没有援助
And no help is coming
因为磁暴已经毁坏了整个北半球
since the magnetic storm has devastated the entire northern hemisphere.
这些磁暴的影响是全球性的
These storms have a planetary footprint.
不仅侵袭整个大陆
They extend not only across entire continents,
而且可以说是肆虐全球
but arguably across the entire planet.
这不仅仅是一场磁暴
It's not just a magnetic storm.
这是一场磁灾
It's a magnetic apocalypse.
经济损失可能高达数十亿  甚至数万亿美元
There would be billions or even trillions of dollars of lost economy.
我们失去的还不止这些
And that's not the only thing lost.
还有很多人会因此丧生
The consequences and the potential for loss of life are quite large,
数目可能达到世界文明地区人口的
perhaps taking out a third to a half of the population
三分之一到二分之一
of the civilized portions of the world.
听起来不可思议吗
Sound unlikely?
但这确实是
But that is exactly
美国国家科学院2009年度的研究报告结论
the conclusion of the National  Academy of Sciences report from 2009.
来自太阳的磁暴
A magnetic storm from the Sun
将彻底摧毁我们的科技基础设施
could wipe out our technological infrastructure,
扼杀数百万条人命
killing millions of people
并将毁灭大部分我们心目中的21世纪的文明
and destroying much of what we think of as 21st century civilization.
这不仅仅是猜测
It's not just guesswork.
太阳磁暴确实在1989年摧毁了魁北克电网
A solar magnetic storm actually knocked out power to Quebec in 1989,
令这个加拿大省份全面停电
blacking out an entire Canadian province.
但是那场磁暴很小
But that storm was small.
我们将面临的磁暴威力是三十多年来前所未有的
We're seeing storm events over the last 30 years or so
其威力将是1989年那场磁暴的10倍
that jumped up literally 10 times larger than that 1989 storm.
新一代太阳人造卫星
A new generation of solar satellites
已经显示了  这些太阳耀斑的威力何等巨大
has revealed just how big these solar flares are,
以及我们的星球是多么不堪一击
and how vulnerable our planet is.
我们这个社会并没有准备好
As a society, we are not prepared for
应付长时期的停电生活
a long-term blackout of the power grid.
我们能阻止这一幕的发生吗
Can this scenario be prevented?
也许
Possibly.
但是只有先弄清楚
But only by understanding
宇宙中最为基本的力量
one of the most basic forces of the universe
也是最不可思议的力量  磁力
and one of the least understood: magnetism.
要理解很多物理现象  磁力是关键
Magnetism is key to understanding a lot of physics
因为它影响着很多事
Because it affects a lot of things.
星球的聚合
It affects how stars condense.
星系的形成
It affects how galaxies form.
黑洞的塌陷
It affects how black holes collapse.
磁力无所不在  蕴含在万物之中
Magnetism is everywhere and in nearly everything.
它是物理中四个基本力量之一
It is one of the four fundamental forces of physics,
它使宇宙凝聚在一起
The forces that keep the universe itself together.
物理学家们已经识别出
Physicists have identified
构成自然的四种基本力量
four fundamental forces at play in nature.
强核力使原子聚合在一起
There's a strong nuclear force that holds atoms together;
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯天文台
弱核力也能
The weak nuclear force, that also has to do with
将原子和粒子聚合在一起
holding together particles and atoms;
然后是重力  我们都很熟悉它
And gravity, with which we are all familiar,
最后一个就是电磁力
And then electromagnetism is the fourth.
电和磁可以说就是一回事
Electricity and magnetism are really one and the same thing.
在这些基本力量中
For something so fundamental,
磁力经常会被忽视
Magnetism often gets overlooked.
除了在冰箱上粘一张便条
Besides holding notes on your refrigerator,
磁铁很少出现在人们的日常生活中
magnets rarely show up in an average person's daily life.
我们通常不怎么用到磁力
Magnetism is not something that we normally deal with.
你感觉不到磁场
You can't feel a magnetic field.
把磁铁从自己身上掠过时  你感觉不到任何东西
You can run a magnet over yourself and you don't feel a thing.
所以日常生活中我们感觉不到磁力
So it isn't part of our daily experience.
磁力的关键在于
The key component of magnetism
吸引和排斥
is that it attracts and repels.
我用这两块磁铁来说明
I'm holding here two magnets to illustrate
磁场怎么发挥作用
how magnetic Fields work
以及磁力有多大
and, frankly, how strong they are.
现在  它们相互吸引
Right now, they're attracting one another
我得用力拉才能把它们分开
and I have to really pull to pull them apart.
但是它们也能相互排斥
But they also can repel each other,
通过把它放在这个杆上就可以说明
And I can illustrate it by putting it on this post.
我把第一块放下去
If I put first one down
然后放下第二块
and drop the second one,
第二块确实放不下去
I really can't push it down.
它弹起了
It just bounces.
事实上  使人们不能穿墙而过
In fact, the only thing that keeps people from walking through walls
也不能穿越楼板掉下楼的唯一力量  就是磁力
or falling through the floor is magnetism.
分子原子极其小
Molecules and atoms are extremely small
原子之间的空隙又极其大
and the space between atoms is extremely large.
以原子来看  每一个事物都有着巨大的空间
At an atomic level, almost everything is made of empty space.
原子核中  电子围绕着质子运转
The distance between the electrons that are orbiting around
两者之间的距离是相当大的
the protons in the nucleus is fairly immense.
就像这个风扇
It's like this fan.
假设扇叶就是电子
If you let the electrons be the blade
中心就是原子核
and the center be the nucleus,
如果风扇没有动起来
If there's no motion taking place there,
其他东西就可以从中穿过
you would pass right through things.
它不是连成一片的
It's not solid.
为什么它连成了一片
So why is it solid?
因为带负电荷的电子
It's because the electromagnetic attraction between
和带正电荷的质子之间
the negatively charged electron
在电磁作用下相互吸引
and the positively charged proton,
电磁吸引使它绕转起来
It captures it and it spins around.
如果绕转速度非常快
So if it's spinning really fast
就像这个风扇的扇叶
like the fan blades of this fan
表示围绕着原子的电子
representing the electrons around the atom,
其他东西会被弹开
it bounces right off.
那就是你不会穿越楼板掉下楼
That's why you don't fall through the floor
也不能穿墙而过的原因
and why you can't walk through walls.
并不是原子本身
It's not the atoms themselves,
而是磁场  使得物质连成一片
but the magnetic field that makes matter solid.
因此人们不能穿墙而过
That keeps a person from walking through walls.
磁力沿着磁力线
Magnetic force attracts and repels
产生吸引和排斥作用
along field lines.
拿一块磁棒
You can take the bar magnet
然后放一张纸在上面
and lay a piece of paper over it
在纸上撒上铁屑
and cover that piece of paper with iron filings.
这些铁屑就会
And the iron filings will actually line themselves up
沿该磁场的磁力线排列起来
along the field lines coming out of the magnet.
这是个好办法
And that's a good way to see
能观察到磁场的样子
what the magnetic field actually looks like.
另一个办法是把这些磁力线想像成
One way to think of field lines
高速公路的车道
is like lanes on a freeway.
南行方向的车流与北行方向的车流互不相干
The south-bound traffic never interacts with the north-bound traffic.
电磁场线就像高速公路的车道
Electromagnetic field lines are like lanes on a freeway:
车都沿着高速路的车道开
Cars go down the lanes, down the freeway.
那就是为什么当你看太阳表面时
And that's why if you look on the surface of the Sun,
会看见许多美丽的弧
you see these beautiful arcs
那就是等离子沿着流动的磁力线
That represent the field lines where the plasma can flow.
但是在太阳的表面
But on the surface of the Sun,
这些磁力线含有巨大能量且致命
these field lines are intensely powerful and deadly.
用高速公路来作比方
In this freeway analogy,
试想如果在公路上的南北向高速行驶的车流中
imagine if a middle lane was opened up on the freeway
开了一条中间的车道
between the speeding north and south traffic.
而且也没有一个路牌
And there is no instruction
来说明哪个方向的车应该走这条道
as to who is supposed to go on that lane.
那么  这条车道
You'll get a big mash up right there
就会一团混乱
where the car is.
每个人都想驶上这条车道
Everyone is trying to go on that lane
随之而来就会发生混乱以及会释放出大量能量
and chaos ensues and there's a big release of energy.
现在再试想一下
Now imagine
这条高速路就在太阳表面
if this freeway was on the Sun
这段车流足有两万英里长
and the cars were 20,000 miles long.
这起巨大的事故导致太阳向外发射物质
The enormous crash fires material off the Sun
径直冲向地球
and straight toward our planet.
这就是日冕物质抛射
That is a Coronal Mass Ejection.
CME非常巨大
A CME is gigantic,
含有超过十亿吨的太阳等离子体
over 10 billion tons of solar plasma.
相当于10万艘航空母舰
It's the equivalent of 100,000 aircraft carriers
以每小时数百万英里的速度冲向地球
traveling at several million miles per hour toward Earth.
这威胁到我们整个星球
This is the threat to our planet.
日冕物质抛射通常不会直接攻击地球
A direct hit from a CME is a rare occurrence,
但是一旦攻击  就会给我们的文明带来巨大灾难
but it would be catastrophic for our civilization.
只消一场大磁暴
We're literally one big storm away
就能给我们的工程带来灭顶之灾
from an engineering disaster.
来自太阳能科学的最新报告让我们更加明了
The sheer size of that disaster has only become clear
灾难的规模之宏大
with new reports from the cutting edge of solar science.
来自卫星的令人不安的新信息
Disturbing new information from satellites
也许能帮助我们预测
might help us predict
下一个致命性的超级大磁暴
the next deadly blast of a magnetic superstorm.
直到最近  人们才发现
Magnetic solar storms have only recently been
太阳磁暴是地球的致命威胁
shown to be a deadly threat to the Earth.
太阳一直在向外抛射物质
The Sun is constantly ejecting material,
从放射物到X射线
from radiation to x-rays
到太阳耀斑  到日冕物质抛射  种种皆有
to solar flares to coronal mass ejections.
这些物质通常没有击中我们
The reason these ejections don't routinely hit us
是因为地球有保护层
is that Earth is protected.
地球被巨大的磁场所包围
The Earth has this huge magnetic field surrounding it.
特拉维斯·斯·泰勒
物理学家
它包围着整个地球
It's all around the thing.
无论是太阳耀斑
and what happens is, if there's a solar flare,
还是日冕物质抛射
a coronal mass ejection,
我们的磁场就是我们的救星  我们的盔甲
our magnetic field is our savior, it's our armor.
比方说  这地球仪
Imagine the Earth
就是我们的地球
as this globe,
而太阳此时是这支猎枪
and the Sun is a shotgun.
太阳每隔几天
The Sun fires off powerful blasts
便向地球攻击一阵
toward the Earth every few days.
但地球
But the planet
有一层防护罩
has a protective shield,
就像一块树脂玻璃板
like a sheet of Plexiglas
可以保护这只地球仪
that protects a globe
免遭子弹射中
from shotgun blasts.
它叫磁层
It's called the magnetosphere,
是由地球剧烈流动的内核
a gigantic magnetic field
发出的强烈磁场
generated by the planet's churning core.
外延足有四万三千英里
It extends out 43,000 miles.
就像两条环形磁铁
Just as a ring magnet
互相排斥一样
repels another ring,
地球的磁层也会排斥
Earth's magnetosphere repels
来自太阳的磁化等离子体
the magnetized plasma from the Sun.
十亿吨过热的
A billion tons of superheated,
并带电的等离子
electrically-charged plasma
向地球袭来
hits our planet,
但通常只是在地球周围打转
and normally just rolls around it.
地球外层的电磁场
The electromagnetic shield
是地球的防护盾
of the Earth is a shield.
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯天文台
带电粒子想进入地球
Charged particles try to get in,
但会被磁场弹回并改换方向
but they bounce against and get redirected by the magnetic field.
只有极小的一部分磁暴
Only a tiny piece of the magnetic storm
能够通过地球的两极的缝隙进入
gets caught in the small opening at the planet's poles,
这便是我们所称的北极光
where we see it as the northern lights.
地球的磁场将高能粒子指引至地球两极
Earth's magnetic field redirects energetic particles to the poles of the Earth.
在看到北极光和南极光的时候  那便是它们
And we see that when we see the northern and southern lights.
这些粒子与地球大气层互相作用  引起极光
Those particles interact with the Earth's atmosphere and cause it to glow,
便是漫天美丽光炫
and it's a beautiful light display.
磁层能改变电磁材料的方向
The magnetosphere can redirect electromagnetic material
而电磁材料正是地球繁荣不可或缺之物
which allows life to flourish on Earth.
没有它  放射性粒子
Without it, radioactive particles
很可能会杀死所有生命形态
would likely kill off all forms of life.
幸运的是  这层防护盾引走一些材料
Fortunately, the field directs away some material,
如太阳耀斑  但却允许其他材料进入地球大气层
like solar flares, and allows other materials in to our planet's atmosphere,
如光和热
like light and heat.
你可能会好奇
You might wonder how is it
磁层保护我们免于日冕物质抛射侵袭
that our magnetosphere protects us from coronal mass ejections.
太阳光却可以长驱直入
but the Sunlight still comes right through
普照大地
and we have daylight.
这是因为日冕物质抛射
Well, that's because the coronal mass ejection
大多都是带电粒子
is mostly charged particles.
磁场能阻拦的
And it's the electric charge
正是这些电荷
that the magnetic field grabs a hold to and traps.
光不含电荷
Light has no electric charge.
由于它不是带电粒子
and since it's not a charged particle,
便可以通过磁场
it passes right on through the magnetic field
毫无影响
like it's not even there.
但地球的强力磁场又是从哪儿来的呢
But where does the planet's powerful magnetic force come from?
我们可由一种历史最悠久
That can be answered with one of the oldest
也是最简单的磁力计得出答案
and simplest of magnetometers,
罗盘
A compass.
这是一只罗盘
I've got a compass here.
快速
金属回收
它能告诉你北在哪个方向  是种非常简单的仪器
It's a pretty simple device to tell you which direction is north.
它是依靠磁场来指向
It uses magnetic fields,
所以有时候它指的方向也不一定正确
so sometimes it doesn't always Point that way.
让我来告诉你们为什么
And I want to show you why it doesn't.
咱们现在在一个废品收购站
We're here at a junkyard.
在我身后  是一个强磁场
And behind me is a huge electromagnet.
当强磁场工作的时候
And when we turn that thing on,
会发生什么呢
what's gonna happen?
让我们来瞧一瞧
Let's take a look.
指针指向强磁场的方向
The compass turned tord the magnet.
但关掉强磁场后
But when we turn that off,
指针会回到北的方向
it's gonna turn back and point to the north.
这说明
And what that tells us
罗盘并不一定指向北
is a compass doesn't point to the north.
它指的是附近最强大的磁场方向
It points to the nearest largest magnetic field.
实际上  罗盘指的也不真是北极
In fact, compasses don't really point to the north pole.
而是指向加拿大埃尔斯米尔岛西部的一堆巨石
They point to a chunk of rock west of Ellesmere Island Off Canada.
那里是地磁北极
This is the magnetic north pole.
北极并不是一个磁极
But the north pole is not a magnet itself.
磁场其实是由地球深处的力产生的
The magnetic field is actually generated by forces deep within the planet.
磁场由移动流产生
Magnetic fields are generated by moving currents
地球  其实就是一个巨大的运动流
And the Earth is one big moving current.
地球自转  而地球内部是熔融液体
The Earth spins and the interior of the Earth is molten and liquid.
有点像这杯红酒
It's kind of like this glass of wine,
当我旋转它时  内部产生有组织的运动
when I swirl it around, it has a nice organized motion.
围绕杯沿
And it hugs the rim of the glass.
地球内核运动大概就是这样
That's kind of what happens inside the Earth's core.
地核中的熔融金属旋转  引发磁场
Molten iron in the core swirls around and generates a magnetic field.
我们的地球其实就是一个发电机
Our planet is actually a dynamo,
将机械能转化为磁能
a device that transfers mechanical energy to magnetic energy.
发电机
Dynamos.
地球里有一个  太阳里有一个
There's one on the Earth, there's one on the Sun,
我自行车上也有一个
and there's one on my bike.
当轮子旋转时
As you see as the wheel turns,
轮轴也随之运动
it's turning the axle in this dynamo.
轮轴周围有磁铁
There are magnets attached to the axles.
于是磁铁旋转
The magnets are spinning around.
磁铁周围有一圈电线缠绕
There's a coil of wire wrapped around there,
于是旋转磁铁产生电场
and that spinning magnet is inducing an electric field,
电流通过导线  达到这灯
and current into this wire, it runs up to this light.
当我踩踏板的时候
And as I spin the pedals,
它便将动能转化为电能  再转化为光能
you see it converts the kinetic energy to electrical energy to light energy.
发电机的关键在于运动
The key for a dynamo is motion.
运动的液体能产生电磁能
Moving fluid can create electromagnetic energy
就像转动的自行车胎
just as much as a moving bike tire.
实际上  液体创造了地球上最强的磁力
In fact, fluid creates the most powerful magnetic force on the planet
这个液体发电机叫做地核
in the fluid dynamo called Earth's core.
但这古老的发电机有个问题
But there's a problem with this ancient dynamo.
它可以自发停止  或改变方向
It can stop or change direction.
地球磁场并不稳定
Earth's magnetic field is not a stable, static thing.
随着时间的过去  它经常改变
It's changed quite a lot over time.
如同杯中的红酒
Like the wine in the glass,
地球磁场可以改变方向
Earth's magnetic dynamo can change direction.
北极和南极可以互换
The north and south pole can literally flip.
究竟是什么引起了两极互换
Exactly what causes the poles to reverse
还是一个未解之谜
is not completely understood.
我们只知道  它经常发生
All we know is that it happens.
我们还知道  地球的磁极
We know that the orientation of the Earth's magnetic poles
本杰明·维斯
麻省理工学院
每几十万年改变一次方向
switches every few hundred thousand years.
冰核以及深海地质学研究揭示
Ice cores and deep-sea geology reveal evidence
大约78万年前
that 780,000 years ago,
罗盘指的方向应该是南边
compasses would have pointed south.
再之前的5万年
50,000 years before that,
指的应该是北边
a compass would have pointed north.
这是地球的循环改变
It's a recurring pattern on our planet
很有可能再次发生
and it may happen again.
我们几乎可以确定
It's almost certain
地球的磁场会再次改变方向
that Earth's magnetic field will change direction again,
但我们不知道确切时间
but we don't know how soon.
实际上
In fact,
上一次磁场逆转是在78万年前
the last magnetic reversal was 780,000 years ago,
这比以往的磁场逆转平均时间要长
which is longer than, on average, the field reverses.
因此在某种意义上磁场逆转已经推迟了
So, in a sense, we're overdue for a reversal.
磁极逆转对人类生活的影响程度尚无定论
No one is sure how a pole reversal will affect human life.
罗盘会掉转指向
Compasses will point south.
鸟类的迁徙行为会陷入混乱
Bird migrations might be disrupted.
GPS的导航也会受到干扰
GPS navigation will be affected.
但这些后果还不是最令人忧心的
But there is a more disturbing consequence.
两极的逆转可能导致某段时期内
A pole reversal might mean a period where there is a weakened
地磁场被弱化  甚至消失
or no magnetic field on the planet.
问题在于  地磁场一旦被弱化
The problem is that the magnetic field, when it gets weak,
地球便失去阻隔太阳微粒辐射的有效挡板
it's no longer an effective shield against particle radiation from the Sun.
假设地球是个有树脂玻璃做挡板的地球仪
Imagine the Earth as a globe with a plexiglass shield.
而此时挡板已经受损
Only now the shield is weakened.
一股来自太阳的高能冲击便足以造成重创
A high-powered blast from the Sun can do immense damage.
当磁极逆转期来临时
When the overdue pole reversal takes place,
地球的保护磁层便会消失
Earth's protective magnetosphere may disappear,
地球将完全暴露在
leaving the entire planet vulnerable
致命的太阳磁暴面前
to deadly magnetic storms from the Sun.
太阳磁暴对地球生物构成的威胁令人担忧
Solar magnetic storms pose a disturbing threat to life on our planet.
在太阳表面
On the surface of the Sun,
耀斑开始沸腾  滚动  然后爆发
a flare begins to boil, bubble, then explode.
太阳表面发生了极为剧烈的爆炸
It's a horrendous explosion on the surface of the Sun.
特拉维斯·斯·泰勒
物理学家
接下来产生巨大的风暴  即日冕物质抛射
And you have this huge storm, a coronal mass ejection.
这些电离粒子以极高的速率飞离太阳
These ionized particles fly away from the Sun at extreme velocities.
这些前所未有的照片来自NASA新发射的卫星
These are unprecedented images from NASA's new satellite
名为SDO  意即太阳动力学观测站
called SDO, the solar dynamics observatory.
人类从未如此近距离地观察过我们的主星
Never before has humanity had such a close look at our home star.
这个观测站和以往观测站最大的区别在于
The big difference between this observatory and previous observatories
托德·霍克斯马
斯坦福大学
它能每时每刻都观测到太阳的整体
is that we're looking at all of the Sun all of the time.
此前我们只能观测到一小部分而非全局
Previously, we've looked at small areas, not the whole disk.
SDO发射于2010年2月  用于检测
Launched in February of 2010, the SDO measures
磁力  紫外线甚至太阳内部的情况
magnetism, ultraviolet rays and even the interior of the Sun.
SDO已传回前所未有的特写照片
Already, SDO has returned never-before-seen close-ups
包括耀斑  磁雨
of solar flares, magnetic rain,
以及掠过太阳表面的海啸
and tsunamis that ripple across the surface of the Sun.
它就像一个数字录像机
It's like having a DVR.
你可以倒回到有趣的画面
You can go back, and you can catch the interesting part
还能随时重复播放
and having an instant replay.
我们发现之前未被揭示的关联性
So we're gonna see connections that we've never seen before.
其中最重要的一点是
One of the most important connections is that
所有的太阳活动本质上都是磁活动
all solar activity is basically magnetic activity.
要理解太阳的易变性  关键在于磁力
The key to understanding the variability of the Sun is magnetism.
我们观测到的有太阳黑子  暗条和爆炸
We see Sunspots, we see filaments, we see explosions.
还观测到日冕物质抛射
We see coronal mass ejections,
即太阳物质通过大爆炸进入宇宙空间
big explosions of material into space.
弄清楚这些现象之间联系的关键
The only way to understand how that all ties together is
在于磁场
through the magnetic field.
太阳的磁力源于
The Sun's magnetism is created
超高温等离子体在其表面的快速运动
by the movement of superheated plasma as it ripples across the surface of our home star.
磁力产生的原因之一是运动流
One of the ways in which magnetism is generated is by a moving current.
任何流动或运动的电荷都能产生磁场
So any flowing, moving charges will generate a magnetic field.
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯天文台
太阳就相当于大量运动电荷的巨大的集合体
The Sun is one huge bag of flowing, moving charges.
在地球上能观测到的磁力现象之一
One of the magnetic phenomena that can actually be seen from Earth
就是太阳黑子
is a Sunspot.
你可以看到太阳黑子
Now if you look at the Sun and you see a Sunspot.
就像一个黑点
It looks like a dark spot.
事实上是磁场本身产生了某种螺旋式扭曲
What's really happening is the magnetic field is twisted up on itself in a certain way.
看起来有点像拔开浴缸的排水口后
It looks kinda like when you pull the drain out of a bathtub
水旋流入下水道的情景
and it spirals down into the drain.
在太阳表面产生了旋风
You create sort of a Tornado, a vortex, on the surface of the Sun.
一个强大的电磁场便产生了
And you have extremely strong electromagnetic fields there.
太阳黑子引发的更严重的后果是太阳耀斑
A Sunspot can lead to something far more dramatic: a solar flare.
发生在太阳上的爆炸
There are explosions on the Sun.
我们称之为太阳耀斑
We call them solar flares.
太阳耀斑可能小至相当一个原子弹的威力
Solar flares Can be either fairly small, by which I mean the size of an atomic bomb,
也可能大至相当于十亿原子弹
or they can be as big as a billion atomic bombs
同时爆炸的威力
all happening at the same time.
太阳表面上的耀斑弧跨度长达数百万英里
Solar flares arc millions of miles above the surface of the Sun.
这些磁暴远非引人入胜的天文数据能表现
These magnetic storms are more than simply intriguing astronomical data.
太阳磁场造就了
The Sun's magnetic field creates
整个太阳系活跃多变的宇宙环境
a dynamic, ever-changing atmosphere throughout the solar system.
形成了所谓的空间气象
It has come to be called space weather.
空间气象是指当太空环境发生的变化
Space weather is the idea that things that change in space
并对地球上的生物造成影响
can have effects on us here on the Earth.
我们对此应如何监测
And how do we measure that?
又应如何进行预测
How do we learn to predict it?
空间气象会对绕地球运行的卫星产生影响
Space weather can affect satellites surrounding Earth.
耀斑产生的高能X射线
High-powered x-rays from a solar flare
对通讯卫星和导航卫星的影响之大
can cause millions of dollars of damage
相当于造成数百万美元的损失
in communications and navigation satellites.
航天飞机及空间站内的宇航员
Astronauts on the shuttle and space station
需掌握空间气象预报
have to know the space weather forecasts
以避免太空行走时遭受致命的辐射
to avoid deadly radiation during a space walk.
为了对此进行预测  SDO应运而生
These are the kinds of problems the solar dynamics observatory is designed to predict.
预测空间气象对我们而言是一大挑战
Forecasting space weather is one of our big challenges.
我们希望能做得更好
We want to learn how to do it better.
如今很多人不太信任天气预报
Now, most of us don't really trust weather reports too much,
可能会信一点  但不太相信
A little bit, but not too much.
而我们连这也做不到
We're way behind that.
在预测空间气象方面我们仍然举步不前
We're not anywhere close to being able to do that yet with space weather.
空间气象是否有规律可循
Are there regular patterns to space weather?
这正是俄亥俄州克里夫兰的本杰明·E
That's exactly what Benjamin E. From Cleveland, Ohio
向《宇宙》提出的问题
wanted to "Ask the universe."
本杰明给我们发来提问邮件
Benjamin emailed us...
科学能否提前预测太阳耀斑和日冕物质抛射
Can science predict solar flares and CME's before they begin?
本杰明  这个问题很有趣
Interesting question, Benjamin.
我们希望能预测大型日冕物质抛射的精准时间
We'd love to be able to predict exactly when giant coronal mass ejections occur.
结论是大约每隔十一年
It turns out that roughly every 11 years,
太阳黑子的数量就会达到最大值
there's a maximum in the number of Sunspots,
日冕物质抛射和太阳耀斑等相关运动也最为频繁
coronal mass ejections, solar flares and associated activity.
我们能粗略地预测发生的时间
We can predict roughly when that'll occur.
只是无法确定具体是哪一组太阳黑子
However, we can't predict when any particular Sunspot group
或日冕物质抛射发生的时间
or coronal mass ejection will occur.
迄今影响最广的空间气象现象
By far, the most powerful examples of space weather
是日冕物质抛射
are coronal mass ejections.
它们与太阳活动周期息息相关
They are connected to the solar cycle,
在太阳最大年达到峰值
peaking during solar maximum,
每天有多达两到三次爆发
with as many as two or three per day.
爆发开始时  是美丽的太阳风暴
They begin with beautiful solar storms,
SDO以全彩色照片将其记录下来
witnessed by the solar dynamics observatory in full color.
一股磁场飓风将不断增强并形成旋涡
A hurricane of magnetic fields will grow and swirl,
散发着弧形和羽状的燃烧的等离子体
sending arcs and plumes of flaming plasma
覆盖了太阳表面几千英里
thousands of miles over the surface of the Sun.
有时候会平静几天
Sometimes these structures are stable for days
或者甚至几周
or even weeks at a time,
然后就会有点什么来触发
And then something will happen to trigger
一场巨大的日冕物质抛射
a release of the coronal mass ejection.
其中一部分会突然升空
And all of a sudden, one part will lift off,
然后就是一场巨大的抛射
and then there'll be a huge lift off,
进入太空
and then it will go off into space.
带电等离子体的巨大爆炸
The gigantic burst of charged plasma
冲向我们的星球
heads toward our planet
不过通常只是围绕我们的磁层流动
where it usually flows harmlessly around our magnetosphere.
但是地球的磁场有个问题
But there's a problem with Earth's magnetic field.
它开始变化了
It's beginning to change.
地磁未来最坏的情况
And the worst-case scenario for Earth's magnetic future
就是像火星表面一样寒冷且没有生命
is the cold, dead surface of Mars.
要不是我们有磁层作为保护的话
Magnetic storms may well be able to bring civilization to a standstill,
磁暴也许会令文明中断
if it weren't for the protective power of our planet's magnetosphere.
如果地球有磁场的话  其他星球呢
If Earth has a magnetic field, do other planets?
按照NASA的说法  这是关键
It's a vital question, according to NASA,
因为其他星球的磁性
because other planets' magnetic properties
也许会预示地球的未来
may reveal the future of Earth.
一  零  发射
1, 0, lift off.
发射
We have a lift off.
仅在太空计划开始之时
Only with the beginning of the space programs,
在二十世纪六十年代  我们已经可以
in the 1960s have we been able
探测其他星球的磁场
to detect the magnetic fields of other planets.
结果令人吃惊
And the discoveries are surprising.
四个大行星
All four of the giant planets:
木星  土星  天王星和海王星
Jupiter,Saturn, Uranus, and Neptune,
现在全都有着活跃的磁场
all have actively generated magnetic fields today.
木星的磁场是太阳系最强的
Jupiter's magnetic field is the strongest in the solar system.
本杰明·维斯
麻省理工学院
它表面的磁场强度是地球的十倍
Its surface field is about 10 times the strength of the Earth's.
木星的磁场
Jupiter's magnetic field
从表面延伸超过四百万英里
stretches over four-million miles from its surface,
它的功能跟地球磁场一样
and it performs the same function as Earth's field.
我们在木星和土星上见到了北极光
We see northern lights on Jupiter and Saturn,
那跟我们地球上的北极光
which is exactly the same interaction
是一样的原理
that we have northern lights on Earth.
是来自太阳的粒子集中在
It's particles from the Sun being focused
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯天文台
这些行星的磁层形成的两极
to the poles of those planets by those planets' magnetospheres
它们就像在地球上一样照亮了大气层
And they light up the atmosphere just like they do on Earth.
但是离太阳越近
But closer to the Sun,
行星的磁场就越弱  令人费解
planetary fields are mysteriously less common.
水星的磁层很弱  大约是地球的百分之一
Mercury has a very weak magnetosphere, about 1% of Earth's.
金星则根本没有磁层
Venus has virtually none.
最神秘的是那个红色的星球  火星
And the most mysterious of all is the red planet, Mars.
九十年代末  火星环球探测者飞船
In the late nineties, the Mars Global Surveyor spacecraft,
它的轨道就围绕着火星
which was in orbit around Mars,
飞船上有一个磁力计
had a magnetometer aboard.
磁力计发现
That magnetometer found
火星没有一个球形的磁场
that Mars does not have a global magnetic field.
但是火星探测者发现
But the Mars surveyor found evidence of
火星表面散布着小磁场
small magnetic Fields scattered on the face of the planet.
NASA认为那是古地磁
NASA believed it was paleomagnetism,
即数十亿年前留下的古代残迹
an ancient remnant from a period billions of years ago.
火星曾经有过跟地球一样的磁场吗
Did Mars once have a magnetic field rivaling Earth's?
如果是  那它怎么样了
And if so, what happened to it?
我们很幸运  不必去那颗红色的星球调查
Fortunately, we don't have to go to the red planet to investigate,
因为它的碎片已经在这里了
because pieces of the red planet are already here.
我们的确有样品  来自火星的岩石
We actually have samples, rocks from Mars.
是陨石
They're meteorites.
由于数百万年前
They were blasted off of Mars
一次小行星或彗星的撞击  它们从火星飞了出来
by an asteroid or comet impact millions of years ago.
这些岩石在宇宙中游荡
These rocks wandered around in space,
其中一些偶然地落到了地球上
And then some of them landed on the Earth randomly.
这些火星陨石中有一块真的很有名
One of these martian meteorites is actually famous:
ALH84-001ALH 84-001.
一些科学家已经表明
Some scientists have suggested
它含有古代火星生命的残骸
it contains the remains of ancient martian life-forms.
不管这一点能否证实
Whether or not this proves true,
这块岩石也许可以回答关于火星磁力的问题
this piece of rock may answer the question of Martian magnetism.
ALH84-001是已知来自所有行星中最老的岩石
ALH 84-001 is the oldest known rock from any planet
它是来自火星的唯一样本
and it is a unique sample from Mars.
它经历了最早的火星历史纪元
It lived through the earliest epoch of Martian history.
所以它里面有各种令人着迷的印记
So this sample has all kinds of fascinating records in it.
麻省理工学院的超导量子显微镜  也叫乌贼
MIT's superconducting quantum microscope, or "Squid,"
是地球上最灵敏的磁力探测器之一
is one of the most sensitive magnetic detection devices on Earth.
一个来自于火星陨石的样本
A sample from the Martian meteorite
在乌贼的镜头下交出了令人吃惊的结果
gives up startling results under the squid lens.
我们发现这块岩石是磁化的
We showed that this rock is magnetized and the magnetism,
这个古地磁可以精确地追溯
the paleomagnetism has been very precisely dated
到大约40亿年前
to be about four billion years old.
这块陨石表面之下
Beneath the surface of the meteorite
是古老的火星磁层的记录
is the ancient record of Mars' magnetosphere.
40亿年前  火星内核中搅动的岩浆
Four billion years ago, a strong magnetic field
产生了一个强大的磁场
was generated by churning magma in the planet's core.
早期的有地磁的火星
Early magnetic Mars was
跟我们现在看到的完全不同
a fundamentally different place than the one we see today.
我们认为当时的大气层
The atmosphere we think at that time
比现在的厚得多
was much thicker than it is today.
也许表面还有水流
There was probably water flowing on the surface.
气候温暖
Temperatures were warmer.
所以比现在更像地球
So it was much more Earth-like.
后来不知为什么  火星死了
Then, mysteriously, Mars died.
温度下降  水也干了
Temperatures dropped. Water vanished.
大气层消失了  发生了什么呢
The atmosphere disappeared. What happened?
火星的磁场在大约41亿年前消失了
Mars' magnetic field died sometime around 4.1 billion years ago.
真正令人着迷的是
What's really fascinating about that is
磁场的消失跟火星开始发生变化基本是同时发生的
it seems to be roughly coincident with the time when Mars began to change
从早期温暖湿润的状态
from an early warm, wet state
变成现在寒冷干燥的情况
to its current cold and dry conditions.
对于火星大气层的消失有种假设
One hypothesis for why Mars' atmosphere disappeared
就是因为它没有了磁层的保护
is because it didn't have a magnetosphere to help protect it.
所以来自太阳的离子流不断地
So the solar wind was constantly stripping away
托德·霍克斯马
斯坦福大学
侵蚀火星大气层
parts of the Mars atmosphere.
没有了磁力盔甲
Without magnetic armor,
日冕物质抛射会轰炸火星的表面
a coronal mass ejection would bombard Mars' surface,
磁力飓风也会撕开它的大气层
A magnetic hurricane that would tear away the planet's atmosphere.
大气层突然失去大量的气体
Suddenly, the atmosphere was losing large quantities of gases
比如氧气  氩气  氮气
like oxygen, argon, nitrogen.
大气层越来越薄
The atmosphere got thinner over time.
液态水也无法停留在火星表面了
Liquid water stopped being stable on the surface.
火星有点进入停滞  寒冷干涸的停滞
And Mars kinda went into a stasis, a cold, dry stasis.
但是地球会发生这样的事情吗
But could it happen on Earth?
当然  在某一时刻
Certainly, at some point,
地球的磁场将会消失
the Earth's magnetic field will shut down.
但是那还早着呢
But that's a long way off.
更紧要的问题是
A more immediate issue
地磁场何时倒转
is when will the Earth's magnetic field reverse.
正如我们所见
As we saw earlier,
地球的磁场每隔几十万年就会倒转一次
our planet reverses its field every few hundred thousand years,
而这一次迟迟未到
and we're overdue.
在地磁场倒转的过程中
When the Earth's magnetic field reverses,
地球会失去磁层的保护
the process may leave Earth without a protective Magnetosphere
这种情况会持续几天  甚至更长
for a period of days or even longer.
火星的悲剧很有可能因此重演
This could lead to the very real possibility of the Mars scenario.
我们将会看到
We're gonna see magnetic storms like
现代文明时代从未经历过的磁暴
we've never really experienced since modern civilization.
但是  未必需要等到行星磁场转换的那天
But we don't need a planetary reversal to wreak havoc.
专家分析  一场磁暴就能
Experts say our entire society
使整个社会陷入浩劫
could be destroyed by a magnetic storm.
想要避免星球被毁灭的命运
Planetary disaster might be avoided,
必须尽快采取措施
but steps must be taken soon,
磁暴灾难迫在眉睫
and the clock is ticking toward magnetic apocalypse.
磁暴是我们太阳系中最强大的力量之一
Magnetic storms are some of the most powerful forces in our solar system,
而它们几乎一直被科学界所忽视
and they've been nearly completely overlooked by science.
磁暴曾经重创过我们的星球
These storms have damaged our planet before.
1989年  一股太阳耀斑袭击了北美
In 1989, a solar flare hit north America,
使魁北克及周围地区的电力系统陷入瘫痪
wiping out power to Quebec and the surrounding area.
在加拿大寒冷的冬天
Six million people
六百万人陷入了无电可用的境地
were without power in the middle of a cold Canadian winter.
一天内  供电恢复
Electricity was restored within a day,
阻止了一场更大的灾难
preventing a greater catastrophe.
然而  袭击魁北克的磁暴只是米粒之珠
But the Quebec storm was a small one.
据记载  1859年发生了一次规模空前的磁暴
A far greater storm was actually recorded in 1859.
往南一直到古巴  都能看见北极光
Northern lights were seen as far south as Cuba.
贯穿美国的电报线路
Telegraph lines stretching across America
被强大的磁浪摧毁  沿线嗡鸣火花不断
hummed and sparked as a massive power surge shorted them out.
这应该是
This may have been
发生过的规模最大的磁暴之一了
one of the largest geomagnetic storms that has ever occurred.
约翰·凯朋玛
电网专家  太阳风暴分析顾问
几乎是1989年袭击北美电网
Literally 10 times larger than what caused the problems
磁暴规模的十倍
in the north American grid in 1989.
来自SDO以及其它天文台的新的观测数据显示
New data from SDO and other observatories show
这些大规模太阳磁暴
that these massive solar storms
要比我们所料想的更加常见
are far more common than we once thought.
如果1859年的大磁暴今天再次袭击地球
What would happen if the same giant storm from 1859
会发生什么呢
hit our planet today?
灾难将始于太阳表面的一次黑子爆发
The disaster would begin with a sunspot erupting on the solar surface,
几十亿吨的太阳物质朝地球喷涌而来
firing billions of tons of material directly at Earth.
不到8分钟
In eight minutes,
伽马射线和X射线将摧毁大多数卫星
gamma rays and x-rays wipe out most satellites.
网络社会一片黑暗
Our wired society is now blinded.
GPS失灵  飞机导航失效
No GPS. No plane navigation.
卫星有线电视关闭
No satellite or cable television.
数以百计的卫星在轨道上行驶
We have hundreds and hundreds of hundreds of satellites in orbit.
特拉维斯·斯·泰勒
物理学家
平均每颗卫星价值五亿美元
And on average, each of those satellites costs a half a billion dollars.
数千亿美元就这么没了
Well, there's hundreds of billions of dollars right there that's gone.
8到16个小时之后  大量日冕抛射物质
Within 8 to 16 hours, the great mass of ejected solar material
将冲击地球磁层
hits Earth's magnetosphere,
瞬间突破它的保护  横扫地球表面
overwhelms it and blasts across the face of the planet.
在设备的大型输电线中
Infrastructure will start seeing large induced currents
开始生成巨大的感应电流
starting to flow through large power lines.
磁暴将引发整个国家的变压器爆炸
It's gonna make power transformers explode all across the country.
变压器瘫痪后
When the transformers go,
美国的每一处电力设备也全都会瘫痪
every piece of electrical equipment in America goes with it.
电力系统起着决定性作用
It's a critical infrastructure,
是所有基础设施的基石
probably the keystone infrastructure.
如果供电被中断
If you take electric supply away,
几乎其他所有的基础设施
virtually all other infrastructures
都会立刻失效  或在几天内失效
will fail either immediately or within just a few days.
饮用水从何而来
Where does your drinking water come from?
供水的许多环节都需要电  才能抽起水来
It needs electricity in a lot of cases to pump the water up.
否则就喝不到饮用水
So you're not gonna have drinking water.
没有自己的发电机  也不会有灯光
You're not gonna have lights unless you have your own generator.
即使有  当发电机燃料耗尽时
And then when the generator runs out of fuel,
你就得跑去加油站
well, if you run down to the gas station
弄些发电机的燃料
to get some more fuel for the generator,
无油供应
可是没有电  油泵无法运行
There's no electricity to run the pumps.
电力一去不复返
The electricity will not come back on,
因为变压器遭到重创  难以修复
because the transformers will be too damaged to repair.
必须重建所有的变压器
They will have to be completely replayed,
这可不是什么简单事
and that is not a simple proposition.
要从头开始建一座单相变压器
It takes at least six months
需要六个月的时间
to build a single transformer from scratch.
这意味着  在六个月内
That means no electricity,
大城市将陷入
no water, no fuel, no banking
无电  无水  燃料匮乏  金融停滞的状态
for six months for major cities.
而小城市要经历的时间则更长
Smaller cities will take longer.
重建一个完整的电网则需要十年以上的时间
To rebuild the entire grid might take over a decade.
修复费用高得难以置信
The cost of repair is staggering.
更令人沉痛的是...那些因此牺牲的生命
The cost in human lives... disturbing.
在这种毁灭性的灾难面前
There is no way that we could sustain a 300 million population
国家无法维持3亿人的生存
in this country with large disruption of that scale.
一些分析表明一场强烈的磁暴
Some estimates suggest that a large magnetic storm
可能会夺去现代世界人口的
could lead to the death of 1/3 to 1/2 of the population
三分之一至二分之一
of the developed world.
也就是1亿美国人  2亿5千万欧洲人
That's 100 million deaths in the U.S., 250 million in Europe,
和10亿亚洲人死于一场磁暴
A billion in Asia, lives lost to the power of a magnetic storm.
直到现在
Up until this time,
我们对这种灾难也没有一个清晰的认识
this sort of disaster has truly been incomprehensible.
我们能做些什么  阻止这场灾难吗
Can anything be done to prevent this type of destruction?
专家们已经开始行动
Experts are trying to plan for that now,
他们对太阳表面的磁暴进行更细致的观察
with better observation of the Sun's explosive magnetic surface,
为电缆设计防护措施
as well as designing shields for cables
并为变压器设立强电振荡防护器
and creating surge preventers for transformers.
现在  我们必须想办法在电网的设计上
We now have to think in ways of retrofitting design changes
做一些改进
into those grids.
对于如何加强这些设施的防护
We're still at early days of trying to figure out
我们仍处于起步阶段
how to harden the infrastructures against these.
磁暴无与伦比的威力揭示了
The apocalyptic power of a magnetic storm reveals
磁是多么普遍而深远地影响了我们的生活
just how essential magnetism is in our lives,
乃至整个宇宙
and in the very universe itself.
电磁是如此重要
Electromagnetism is the most important thing
你会发现它驾驭着我们的日常生活
that you can see that's driving our daily lives.
我想人们不会在意磁现象
I think people don't think about magnetism
劳拉·丹利
格里菲斯天文台
就像水里的鱼不会在意水一样
because it's kind of like a fish in water doesn't think about water.
它无处不在  聚合世间万物
It's everywhere. It holds everything together.
大气因磁而生  呼吸因磁而发
It holds the atmosphere, the action of breathing,
眼睛看见事物的过程是一种电磁交互
the action of seeing is an electromagnetic interaction.
磁力是一种简单的力
Magnetism is a simple force,
是宇宙中四种最基本的力之一
one of four most basic forces in the universe.
它可以成为孩童的玩具
It can become a child's toy,
让我们的分子聚集在一起  幸运的话
it holds our molecules together, and if we're lucky,
它能使我们幸免于太阳放射的巨大能量
it protects our planet from the vast powers of the Sun.
对于地球上的居民来说
To the inhabitants of Earth,
它是宇宙间最被我们忽视的力之一
it is one of the most overlooked forces in our universe.
然而一切  都任其主宰
Yet magnetism gives and can take everything.